Nikolaos Fanourakis

+30 6977057937 · nikosfanourakis5@gmail.com Heraklion, Crete, Greece







PHD CANDIDATE | DATA SCIENTIST

Ph.D. candidate at Computer Science Department of University of Crete, with both academic and industrial working experience in the fields of databases and graph neural networks. Equipped with a theoretical and practical background in graph analytics, machine learning and big data, I can intricate real-world problems and drive data-driven solutions.

SKILLS

- Python • Graph Neural Networks
- SQL LLMs
- JAVA
- Pytorch (Geometric)
- Scala
- Writing/Communication Skills
- Apache Spark
- HTML/CSS/JS
- Graph Theory
- Semantic Web

LANGUAGE SKILLS

- Greek (Mother Language)
- English (B2)
- Italian (B2)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Postgraduate and Doctoral Research Assistant - Data Scientist Information Systems Laboratory, FORTH - ICS

Mar 2020 - Present

- Research project related to entity alignment, using knowledge graph embeddings
- Fairness and Diversity

R&D in Benchmarking Team

June 2024 - August 2024

RelationalAI, Inc, Berkeley (Remote Internship)

- Implementation of benchmarks in PyRel
- Performance analysis

Data Scientist Mar 2020 - Sept 2020

ETIS Laboratory, CY Cergy Paris Université (Remote Internship)

Start of master thesis with title: "Graph Embeddings Methods for Entity Resolution"

Front-End Engineer Omnixell

Apr 2019 - Sept 2019

- Web Development for cross-platform applications using lonic 3
- Angular and Vue.js

Full Stack Web Developer

Jul 2017 - Dec 2018

Information Systems Laboratory, FORTH - ICS

- Thesis: "Speleothem: An information System for Caves Based in Semantic Web technologies"
- Web Development using HTML/CSS/JS
- · Spark microservices
- Ontologies and Triple Stores

EDUCATION

Master in Computer Science CSD of University of Crete

Bachelor in Computer Science CSD of University of Crete

PUBLICATIONS

- Knowledge Graph Embedding Methods for Entity Alignment: Experimental Review. DMKD (2023)
- Structural Bias in Knowledge Graphs for the Entity Alignment Task. ESWC 2023
- FairER demo: Fairness-Aware and Explainable Entity Resolution. ISWC 2023
- Speleothem-An Information System for Caves Based on Semantic Web Technologies. ESWC 2018